WAYNE YOUNG

LEARNER|ACHIEVER|ANALYTICAL|RESPONSIBILITY|INTELLECTION

SUMMARY

Accomplished Technical Professional with 20+ years of proven performance in the utility technology industry. Proactive leader, team builder, and mentor with the ability to identify, hire, train, and motivate top sales performers. Broad background that encompasses exceptional work ethic and technical ability. Noted for leadership skills, problem solving, and ability to sell and deliver large, complex systems within budget and on schedule. Expertise in requirements gathering, understanding the client's business needs and ensuring customer success.

CONTACT

PHONE:

972.377.2526 (H) 214.316.2774 (C)

211131312771(0

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/wayneyoung-1190301/

EMAIL:

wayne@rwysolutions.com

SKILLS

- ✓ Business Development
- ✓ Product Management
- ✓ System Implementation
- ✓ SaaS/DevOps/Azure/SQL/Office 365
- ✓ Mobile Solutions
- ✓ Software Development Life Cycle
- ✓ Legacy System Conversions
- ✓ Written & Verbal Communication
- ✓ Account Management
- ✓ Project Management
- ✓ Defect Resolution
- ✓ Business Analysis
- ✓ Customer Orientated Sales
- ✓ Salesforce CRM
- ✓ IoT/AMI/AMR
- ✓ Workforce Management
- ✓ GIS

EDUCATION

Shepherd University

Shepherdstown, WV, USA

Bachelor of Science

Business Administration (Major) Computer Programming (Minor)

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Director, Water Technology Sales & Development Dec 2015 – Oct 2019
Nighthawk

- ✓ Sold value proposition of smart fire hydrants and permanent pressure monitoring to executive decision makers
- ✓ Negotiated Nighthawk's most profitable multi-year SaaS deal
- ✓ Closed large, complex SaaS deal with Los Angeles Department of Water & Power
- ✓ Created Mobile Strategy enabling all application functions to be performed in the field on any smartphone or tablet
- ✓ Designed mobile & web-based IoT/SaaS remote monitoring system
- ✓ Delivered first to market, permanent, LTE smart hydrant IoT solution
- ✓ Managed successful implementations with San Francisco Water, Redmond, Bend, SCWD and others
- ✓ Directed defect triage and prioritization efforts internally and externally
- ✓ Assisted with firmware and software debugging efforts as needed
- ✓ Prioritized, maintained and updated agile product backlog list
- ✓ Technologies used: .NET, CSS/HTML5, Bootstrap, JavaScript, NodeJS, Angular, SQL Server, Jira, GPS, GIS, LTE, Agile

Solutions Director

Nov 2010 – Dec 2015

Clevest, Inc.

- ✓ Managed a highly skilled Application Development, Delivery and Support team (Developers, Analysts and Testers)
- ✓ Closed \$25M of complex solution sales with largest IOUs in U.S. including AEP, FirstEnergy, Eversource, Consumers, TECO and others
- ✓ Tripled FieldNet sales after acquisition from Neptune Technology Group (Led Clevest Sales Team in total sales, 2011 2015)
- ✓ Managed full life cycle enterprise software projects at major IOUs
- ✓ Partnered with Trimble to build and sell AMR SCM+ ERT handheld
- ✓ Developed and sold new features of workforce management and meter reading solutions for AEP, TECO, FirstEnergy and others
- ✓ Successfully managed FirstEnergy and Allegheny Energy merger of multiple enterprise systems
- ✓ Technologies used: .NET, CSS/HTML, JavaScript, SQL Server, PL/SQL, Oracle, PowerBuilder, C++, Esri, GPS

WAYNE YOUNG

CONTACT

PHONE:

972.377.2526 (H)

214.316.2774 (C)

EMAIL:

wayne@rwysolutions.com

KEY CUSTOMER SUCCESSES

- ✓ Los Angeles Dept Water & Power
- ✓ City of Rio Rancho
- ✓ Suffolk County Water
- ✓ City of Long Beach
- ✓ San Francisco Water
- ✓ City of Redmond
- ✓ City of Bend
- ✓ Procter and Gamble
- ✓ Clow
- ✓ Kennedy
- ✓ Allegheny Power
- ✓ Pacificorp
- ✓ Progress
- ✓ American Electric Power
- ✓ Eversource
- ✓ LGEKU
- ✓ Northeast Utilities
- ✓ FirstEnergy
- ✓ Consumers Energy
- ✓ Centerpoint/Reliant
- ✓ Oncor
- ✓ Green Mountain Power
- ✓ Tampa Electric

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Development Manager

Nov 2003 - Nov 2010

Neptune Technology Group

- ✓ Led full system lifecycle from RFP stage to go live including pre-sales, consulting, executive sales, presentations, scope of work, contract negotiation, development, implementation, customer support and post-deployment enhancement requests for large enterprise projects
- ✓ Managed Development, Delivery and Support team of 12 (Developers, Analysts and Testers)
- ✓ Led effort to start virtualizing application servers
- ✓ Implemented web-based time tracking system to accurately account for time spent on projects and to assist with planning of future projects
- ✓ Brought first combined Windows Mobile, GPS, real-time meter reading and workforce management system to market
- ✓ Technologies used: Oracle, PL/SQL, C++, .NET, PowerBuilder, GPS, MapInfo, Esri, SAP & CC&B interfaces

Senior System Engineer

March 1996 - Nov 2003

DBMicroware/Neptune Technology Group

- ✓ Designed custom meter reading, service order and rerouting software
- ✓ Created detailed project plans in MS Project with well-defined tasks, milestones, client sign-offs, test cycles, and specifications, which served to communicate project progress to management
- ✓ Developed multi-threaded code resulting in 75% decrease in processing time
- ✓ Technologies used: Oracle, PL/SQL, SQL Server, Watcom SQL, PowerBuilder, C++